scripps.org 2016-10-21

# Privacy Policy - Scripps Health

Last Updated: 9/24/14

 **By using this website, you agree to the following Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to all of these terms, please do not use this website. Scripps Health reserves the right to change, modify, add, or delete portions of this Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of this website following any changes to the Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes. Please refer to the date listed above to determine when the last changes were made.**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information collected offline. This information is available on the Notice of Privacy Practices page.

#### Use of personal information/privacy

This website is owned and operated by Scripps Health, a California nonprofit public benefit corporation. By using this site, you agree that Scripps Health may monitor your use of this website and may use the results of such monitoring without limitation.

The information we gather generally can be categorized as either anonymous or personally identifiable.

#### Tracking of anonymous information

Anonymous (or sometimes referred to as “aggregate”) information is information that cannot be traced back to a specific individual. For example, we know how many times our site and certain portions of our site are visited, but we do not know the names, e-mail addresses or gender of our visitors unless they specifically provide that information. We use this anonymous information to obtain a better understanding of how visitors use our website and to make decisions on how to improve it.

Each time a visitor comes to our site, we collect some information in an effort to improve the overall quality of your online experience. We collect the visitor’s referral data (e.g., the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to our website), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Safari browser on a Macintosh platform).

In addition to collecting these types of information, Scripps Health collects aggregate queries for internal reporting. We also count, track, and aggregate the visitor’s activity into our analysis of general traffic flows at our site (e.g., tracking where traffic comes from, how traffic flows within our site, etc.).

In order to determine a user’s ability to receive HTML e-mail in addition to whether or not an e-mail has been opened, a “web beacon” is included in a majority of the HTML e-mail messages sent. A web beacon (actually a small .gif image) is activated when an HTML e-mail is opened via a request for the image on the servers. This capability helps us send e-mail in a format users can read, and enables us to track the aggregate number of e-mails opened.

The web beacon does not collect any personally identifiable information. Users that do not want to receive e-mail messages with web beacons can choose to receive their e-mails in text (non-HTML) format. We also use the capability to track when a URL has been clicked inside of an e-mail message. We use this functionality to track which links were clicked and in what quantity, as well as the aggregate number of links clicked. This click tracking functionality does not collect any personally identifiable information.

#### Tracking of personally identifiable information

During your visit to our website, we may request and collect personally identifiable information from you, such as your name, e-mail address, physical address, telephone number and any other personal information you share with us. The information you will be asked to provide to us is voluntary only; you will always have the option of not providing the information if you so choose.

When a form provides the ability to opt-in to receiving future e-mails from Scripps Health and you choose to opt-in, you will be added to the e-mail list you have selected. This information will not be used for any other purpose. We do, however, reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

You may review and change your information with us at any time by clicking on the “Manage Profile” link found at the bottom of e-mails sent by us. To opt-out from having any provided information used for e-mail communications from us, please click on the opt-out (unsubscribe) link in any message you receive from us. This will allow you to unsubscribe or update your message preferences.

The information we gather from you is used in connection with your interest in employment opportunities with Scripps Health, a class or event, educational needs, if you have questions or comments you would like to share with Scripps Health or related activities.

Scripps Health does not disclose, give, sell, or transfer any personal information to third parties for non-Scripps’ use. Personally identifiable information may be collected from visitors to our site and provided in an aggregate form to other parties within the Scripps Health family for marketing, advertising or other similar uses.

#### E-mail lists and newsletters

You will be added to a Scripps Health e-mail list only if you register to receive e-mails via a form on the Scripps website, a printed form, or during a call to our Call Center at 1-800-SCRIPPS. You may opt-out of receiving our e-mails by clicking on the opt-out link included in every e-mail we send. If you have any issues relating to unsubscribing to Scripps e-mails please contact [webteam@scrippshealth.org](mailto:%77%65%62%74%65%61%6d@%73%63%72%69%70%70%73%68%65%61%6c%74%68.%6f%72%67).

#### Refer a friend/forward-to-a-friend functionality

If you feel that information provided in a Scripps Health e-mail could be useful for someone you know (e.g., your friends or family members), you may use our forward-to-a-friend functionality. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about Scripps Health, we will ask you for your friend’s e-mail address. We will automatically send the person you designate a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the site. Scripps Health stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail and tracking the success of our referral program.

#### Confidential information

We provide several ways to e-mail us with questions you may have as you navigate through our site. Please note that any information sent through an e-mail message is unsecured and can be seen on computers which transfer data from your computer to Scripps Health. **We recommend that you do not e-mail sensitive personal health information, or any other confidential information, to Scripps Health or anyone else.** Should you choose to provide information in this manner, you do so at your own risk.

#### Security

We take precautions to maintain the confidentiality of your information; however, you must keep in mind as you navigate through our website that any message you may send through the website or through e-mail is not secure and may be susceptible to third party interception. As a result, you transmit information to us at your own risk.

#### Cookies

We may place small data files, called “cookies,” in your browser’s file storage area of your computer’s hard drive. Cookies are a standard Internet technology that allow us to both store and retrieve login information on a user’s system. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a site visitor’s computer to gather and keep track of information related to you. These cookies automatically identify your browser to our server whenever you interact with a service provided on our website. Cookies can store your preferences through a password you select to access a website. Cookies also help us review website traffic patterns and improve our site.

Most browsers automatically accept these cookies, but you usually can change your browser setting to prevent the acceptance of cookies, though this may prevent you from using some of the features of our website. Information collected through cookies is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

#### Log files

We collect and log IP addresses in order to analyze site visitation trends and administer the website. An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. IP addresses allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with one another. IP address information allows us to properly administer our system and gather aggregate information on visitors to our website.

IP address information also helps diagnose problems with our servers, and how our site is being used, including the pages visitors are viewing in the aggregate. This aggregate information may be shared with third parties, such as our physicians, our suppliers and other businesses. To maintain your anonymity, we do not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. In other words, IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

#### Links

Our website may contain links to websites that are not operated by Scripps Health. You may be asked by these websites to provide personal information or to release information you may have provided on our site. You are never required to release this information, and whether you do is optional and strictly up to you.

Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these sites, nor any adverse consequences that may result from your interaction with such third party websites. Scripps Health has no control or influence over the privacy practices of these other websites. This would also apply to these sites’ use of cookies and other electronically collected data.

We encourage you to be cautious when leaving our website and review the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected through those websites.

#### Children’s privacy protection

In accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), Scripps Health will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without parental consent. When we do receive information (with parental consent) from users under the age of 13, we will not share their personally identifiable information with third parties, regardless of their stated preference given at registration.

#### Disclosures required to investigate complaints to law enforcement officials

Scripps Health may use personal information collected or in its possession to contact users in connection with their inappropriate use of our website, noncompliance with our Terms of Use, or in connection with a complaint filed about their use of our site by another user.

Scripps Health also may disclose your personal information to another party, such as law enforcement officials, to comply with legal requirements, court orders, government or law enforcement agency requests, to protect or defend Scripps Health, or where we perceive an immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to someone as a result of activity on our site. Our disclosures may occur under circumstances where we may not be authorized to advise you of such action.

#### Changing or deleting information

If you wish to delete or correct your personally identifiable information obtained through this Web site, you may:

  * Send a written request to:  
Web Team,  
Scripps Health,  
10100 Campus Point Drive, AN105,  
San Diego, CA 92121
  * Send an electronic request to: [webteam@scrippshealth.org](mailto:%77%65%62%74%65%61%6d@%73%63%72%69%70%70%73%68%65%61%6c%74%68.%6f%72%67)
  * Submit an electronic request.
  * Call **1-800-SCRIPPS** and submit a verbal request.

#### Comments or questions

Should you have any questions regarding this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with this Web site, you may contact us at [webteam@scrippshealth.org](mailto:%77%65%62%74%65%61%6d@%73%63%72%69%70%70%73%68%65%61%6c%74%68.%6f%72%67).
